Now that we have covered the legal protections in place,
let's look at what this looks like in the real world.
On the screen is a video titled Life and Death Drama.
As we watch this, I want you to notice
that sudden cardiac arrest can truly happen to anyone,
regardless of their age, race, gender, or demographic.
Even though there are often stereotypes
about who is at risk,
these examples show that cardiac arrest
does not discriminate and can happen to anyone at any time.
I want you to notice a specific detail
in how these individuals fall.
Notice that they do not put out their hands
to brace themselves.
This is because cardiac arrest
causes the heart to stop pumping blood immediately.
Because blood flow to the brain is cut off instantly,
the person loses consciousness
and collapses without any warning or time to react.
Recognizing this sudden unprotected collapse
is a key way for you to identify
that someone needs your help right away.